Nancy Sweezy collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Nancy Sweezy collection circa 1850-2009 1968-2007
AFC 2017/001
Nancy Sweezy, 1921-2010
33,037 items.
97 containers.
44.6 linear feet.
16,200 manuscript materials.
3,333 photographs: prints: b&w., col.; various sizes.
5,808 photographs: slides: col.; 35 mm.
approximately 7,488 photographs: film negatives: b&w., col.; 35 mm.
23 photographs: glass negatives: b&w.; various sizes.
130 sound cassettes: analog.
25 videocassettes: analog.
16 optical discs: optical
14 zip disks: digital
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Collection of papers, photographs, interviews, field recordings and other audiovisual materials comprising the professional archive of folklorist Nancy Sweezy created in the course of her career as a folk arts advocate, author, and administrator of non-profit folk craft and performance organizations. Includes research materials for her books Raised in Clay: The Southern Pottery Tradition, Armenian Folk Arts, Culture, and Identity co-edited with Levon Abrahamian and Sam Sweezy and The Potter's Eye: Art and Tradition in North Carolina Pottery co-authored by Mark Hewitt.
Provenance
Martha Sweezy; 2016 and The Country Roads, Inc. Board of Directors; 2021.
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Access and Restrictions
The Nancy Sweezy collection is open for research. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at https://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Biographical Note
Nancy Sweezy, author, folklorist, raised in Concord, New Hampshire, studied at the School of the Museum of Fine Arts in Boston, Massachusetts. During World War II, she worked overseas in the Research and Analysis Branch of the Office of Strategic Services (OSS). Her interest in craft began with pottery lessons in New England in the 1950s. She worked in partnership with Ralph Rinzler and helped manage Club 47 (now Club Passim) in Cambridge, Massachusetts, where she served as president of the board. She and Ralph, along with Norman Kennedy and others, formed Country Roads, Inc. in 1966 to support folk arts educational projects, research, and marketing. The group purchased the Jugtown Pottery in Seagrove, North Carolina, in 1968, and Sweezy moved to North Carolina to direct the operation and work with traditional potters in the area. In the 1980s in Boston, Nancy organized the Refugee Arts Group to encourage recent Southeast Asian and other immigrants to preserve and perpetuate craft, dance, and music traditions from their communities of origin. In the 1990s, Sweezy documented the traditional crafts of Armenia, making more than a dozen trips to the country. In 2006, the National Endowment for the Arts presented Nancy Sweezy with the Bess Lomax Hawes National Heritage Fellowship. She was born October 14, 1921, in Flushing, New York, and died February 6, 2010, in Cambridge, Massachusetts.
Scope and Content
Collection of papers, photographs, interviews, field recordings and other audiovisual materials comprising the professional archive of folklorist Nancy Sweezy created in the course of her career as a folk arts advocate, author, and administrator of non-profit folk craft and performance organizations. Includes research materials for her books Raised in Clay: The Southern Pottery Tradition (Smithsonian Institution Press, 1984; re-published by University of North Carolina Press, 1994), Armenian Folk Arts, Culture, and Identity co-edited with Levon Abrahamian and Sam Sweezy (Indiana University Press, 2001) and The Potter's Eye: Art and Tradition in North Carolina Pottery co-authored by Mark Hewitt (University of North Carolina Press, 2005).
Arrangement
Organized in series according to major projects in the creator’s career, which reflect the general original order of their use.
Series 1: Country Roads, Inc. Administrative (1966-2003)
Series 2: Jugtown Pottery (circa 1850-2001, bulk: 1968-1985)
Series 3: Southern Pottery Interviews, Raised in Clay (1967-1995, bulk: 1981-1994)
Series 4: NEA Site Visits and Apprenticeships, (1977-2004, bulk: 1984-1994)
Series 5: Refugee Arts Group and the Center for Living Traditions (1985-1997, bulk: 1986-1991)
Series 6: Armenia (1987-2008, bulk: 1988-1997)
Series 7: Spirited Objects and OXYGEN Media Project (1996-2001, bulk: 1998-2001)
Series 8: Potter's Eye and Other Projects (1970-2008, bulk: 1995-2007)
Series 9: Personal Files and Correspondence (1923-2009)
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Hawes, Bess Lomax, 1921-2009.; Rinzler, Ralph.; Sweezy, Nancy
Organizations
Club Passim.; Country Roads, Inc.; Jugtown Pottery (Firm); National Endowment for the Arts. Folk Arts Program.; Refugee Arts Group.; Smithsonian Institution. Office of Folklife Programs.
Subjects
Artisans--Armenia (Republic)--Interviews.; Arts administrators--United States--Biography.; Asian Americans--Massachusetts--Social life and customs.; Ethnic arts.; Folk art--Armenia (Republic); Folk art--Massachusetts.; Folklore--Armenia (Republic); Potters--Southern States--Interviews.; Pottery--North Carolina.; Pottery--Southern States.; Public folklore.; Women folklorists--United States--Biography.
Places
Cambridge (Mass.)--Social life and customs.
Form/Genre
Correspondence.; Field notes.; Interviews.; Manuscripts.; Photographs.; Sound recordings.; Videocassettes.
Container List
- Series 1: Country Roads, Inc. Administrative, 1966-2003
  - Country Roads store papers, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 88/1)
  - Country Roads store promotional material, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 90/1)
  - Country Roads - Proposal for a Catalogue of American Handicrafts, 1968-1968 (Box-folder 88/2)
  - Country Roads North Carolina projects - Holt and Brown, 1984-1997 (Box-folder 88/3)
  - Country Roads social at Michela's Café, 1991 (Box-folder 88/4)
  - Country Roads 2002 Celebration, 2001-2003 (Box-folder 88/5-6)
  - Country Roads mailing lists, undated (Box-folder 88/7)
  - Board of directors meeting minutes, 1968-1973 (Box-folder 88/8)
  - Board of directors meeting minutes, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 88/9)
  - Board of directors meeting minutes, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 88/10)
  - Board of directors meeting minutes, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 88/11)
  - Board of directors meeting minutes, 1990-1993 (Box-folder 88/12)
  - Board of directors meeting minutes, 1994-1998 (Box-folder 88/13)
  - Board of directors meeting minutes, 1999-2002 (Box-folder 88/14)
  - Country Roads contact sheets, undated, 27 photographic prints (Box-folder 87/19)
    - Country Roads board material, undated, afc2017001_cf04; text files; original media: CD-ROM
    - Country Roads documents, 1996-1998, afc2017001_cf21; text files; original media: zip disk
    - Country Roads documents, 2000-2005, afc2017001_cf08; text files; original media: CD-ROM
    - Country Roads documents, 2001-2002, afc2017001_cf23; text files; original media: zip disk
    - Country Roads documents, undated, afc2017001_cf07; text files; original media: CD-ROM
- Series 2: Jugtown Pottery, circa 1850-2001, Bulk: 1968-1985
  - Subseries 1: Manuscripts and Photographic Prints
    - Busbee family photographs, ca. 1850-ca. 1875, 14 albumen carte de visite photograph prints, 3 daguerreotypes, 3 ambrotypes (Box 93)
    - Photographs of Jugtown and surrounding areas taken by Jacques and Juliana Busbee, ca. 1915-ca. 1917, afc2017001_ph27; These photographs are available only as digital surrogates. The original photographs were nitrate film negatives and are not available.; AFC 2017/001: ph27_001 to ph27_016
    - Photographs of Jugtown and surrounding areas taken by Jacques and Juliana Busbee, ca. 1915-ca. 1917, AFC 2017/001: ph27_017 to ph27_039; 23 glass plate negatives (Box 94)
    - Jugtown - Busbee photos and printed matter, 1915-1937, 17 photographic prints and mixed manuscript material (Box-folder 48/1)
    - Photographs of Jugtown potters, ca. 1917, 6 photographic prints (Box 95)
    - Jugtown historic recipe book, ca. 1921 (Box-folder 91/1)
    - Documents re: information requested from Smithsonian, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 48/2)
    - Early Country Roads- Jugtown papers, 1969-1980 (Box-folder 48/3)
    - Jugtown - Egg and Eye exhibit, 1969-1969 (Box-folder 48/4)
    - Country Roads Jugtown reports, 1968-1977 (Box-folder 48/5)
    - Jugtown notes - clay and glaze recipes, 1970-1980 (Box-folder 48/6)
    - Jugtown notebook - loose pages - clay and glaze recipes, firing notes, and experiments, 1970-1979 (Box-folder 48/7-8)
    - Jugtown notebook - glaze formulas and production notes, 1970-1979 (Box-folder 48/9)
    - Jugtown - technical pottery info, undated (Box-folder 48/10)
    - Jugtown notes - keep for book, undated (Box-folder 48/11)
    - Jugtown correspondence, 1969-1979 (Box-folder 48/12)
    - Jugtown correspondence, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 48/13)
    - Jugtown papers, 1978-1986 (Box-folder 48/14)
    - Jugtown finances, undated (Box-folder 49/1)
    - Jugtown finances, undated (Box-folder 49/2)
    - Jugtown apprentices, undated (Box-folder 49/3)
    - Jugtown printed matter, undated (Box-folder 49/4)
    - Pottery of Jugtown, undated, 103 photographic prints (Box-folder 12/13)
    - Country Roads: Jugtown, Refugee Arts Group, Center for Living Traditions, Armenia, and portraits, undated, 70 photographic prints (Box-folder 8/2)
    - Jugtown photos, 1968-1978, 3 photographic prints (Box-folder 5/1)
    - Jugtown black-and-white contact sheets, undated, 17 photographic prints (Box-folder 86/7)
    - Jugtown color contact sheets, undated, 7 photographic prints (Box-folder 86/8)
    - Jugtown clippings, 1968-1978 (Box-folder 49/5)
    - Jugtown clippings, 1980-1999 (Box-folder 49/6)
    - Jugtown clippings (scans, multiple per page), 1920-1975, AFC 2017/001: OS2-GR01-GR24; 24 black-and-white pages, 25 x 18 in.
    - Jugtown clippings (scans, multiple per page), 1920-1975, AFC 2017/001: OS3-GR01-GR26; 26 black-and-white pages, 25 x 18 in.
    - Jugtown clippings (scans, multiple per page), 1920-1975, AFC 2017/001: OS4-GR01-GR21; 21 black-and-white pages, 25 x 18 in.
    - Jugtown trip to England, 1976-1976 (Box-folder 49/7)
    - Jugtown - Joan Mondale visit, 1977 (Box-folder 49/8)
    - Jugtown women's exhibit - Michigan, 1978 (Box-folder 49/9)
    - Jugtown - David Leach workshop, 1978 (Box-folder 49/10)
    - David Leach workshop, 1978, 12 photographic prints (Box-folder 12/7)
    - Sale of Jugtown and post-sale Country Roads Board papers, 1979-1985 (Box-folder 49/11)
    - Boston Agriculture Center shows, 1980 (Box-folder 49/12)
    - Book ideas regarding Jugtown, 1980 (Box-folder 49/13)
    - Sale of Jugtown to Country Roads, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 49/14)
    - Jugtown film, 1982 (Box-folder 49/15)
    - Jugtown collection at Mint Museum, 1985 (Box-folder 49/16)
    - Papers collected for memoir - writings regarding Jugtown, undated (Box-folder 49/17)
    - Pamela and Vernon Owens: Potters of Jugtown, 2008 (Box-folder 48/15)
    - Publications featuring Jugtown, undated (Box-folder 50/1-3)
    - Post-Country Roads Jugtown, 1990-1993 (Box-folder 50/4)
    - Jugtown exhibit at McKissick Museum - includes oral history transcripts, 1992-1995 (Box-folder 50/5)
    - Jugtown auction (1993) and prior appraisals, 1993 (Box-folder 50/6)
    - Jugtown auction catalog, 1993 (Box-folder 50/7)
    - Correspondence and info re: Jugtown pottery sale, 1969-1993 (Box-folder 50/8)
    - Photos to send to Vernon, undated, 8 photographic prints and mixed manuscript material (Box-folder 50/9)
    - Clippings re: Ben Owen, 1969-2001 (Box-folder 50/10)
    - Printed matter regarding international potteries, undated (Box-folder 50/11)
    - Printed material - crafts, 1950-1960 (Box-folder 89/1)
    - Printed material - pottery, 1958-1978 (Box-folder 89/2-3)
    - Printed matter regarding US potteries, undated (Box-folder 51/1-2)
    - Printed matter - other North Carolina and Southern Pottery, undated (Box-folder 51/3)
    - "Notes on Clay" by Nancy Sweezy, Shady Hill School, undated (Box-folder 51/4)
    - New Ways for Old Jugs: Tradition and innovation at the Jugtown Pottery (McKissick Museum exhibit book), 1994 (Box-folder 89/6)
  - Subseries 2: Slides and Negatives
    - Turning, undated, AFC 2017/001: ph01_001 to ph01_014 (Box 13-14)
    - Jugtown - early Country Roads days in turning shop, 1976-1978, AFC 2017/001: ph01_015 to ph01_035 (Box 13-14)
    - Wheel work, 1976-1978, AFC 2017/001: ph01_036 to ph01_052 (Box 13-14)
    - John Almquist turning, 1978-1979, AFC 2017/001: ph01_053 to ph01_070 (Box 13-14)
    - Turning bowls, 1976, AFC 2017/001: ph01_071 to ph01_084 (Box 13-14)
    - Vase turning, 1976, AFC 2017/001: ph01_085 to ph01_093 (Box 13-14)
    - Unlabeled, 1976-1978, AFC 2017/001: ph01_094 to ph01_108 (Box 13-14)
    - Clay, 1978, AFC 2017/001: ph01_109 to ph01_123 (Box 13-14)
    - C6 glaze ware loading, 1974-1984, AFC 2017/001: ph01_124 to ph01_142 (Box 13-14)
    - Salt glaze decorating, 1978, AFC 2017/001: ph01_143 to ph01_158 (Box 13-14)
    - Processes after fire, 1978, AFC 2017/001: ph01_159 to ph01_173 (Box 13-14)
    - Firing 3rd groundhog upright, 1973-1978, AFC 2017/001: ph01_174 to ph01_186 (Box 13-14)
    - Jugtown early Country Roads days, horses, kiln work, 1976-1978, AFC 2017/001: ph01_187 to ph01_206 (Box 13-14)
    - Turning candlesticks, 1978, AFC 2017/001: ph01_207 to ph01_218 (Box 13-14)
    - Clay, 1978-1979, AFC 2017/001: ph01_219 to ph01_231 (Box 13-14)
    - Clay prep at Jugtown, 1978, AFC 2017/001: ph01_232 to ph01_251 (Box 13-14)
    - Slides for possible book use, undated, AFC 2017/001: ph01_252 to ph01_263 (Box 13-14)
    - Early Country Roads at Jugtown clay dig, glaze, 1978, AFC 2017/001: ph01_264 to ph01_291 (Box 13-14)
    - Ware: salt, 1975, AFC 2017/001: ph02_001 to ph02_015 (Box 14-15)
    - Ware: salt glaze, 1975, AFC 2017/001: ph02_016 to ph02_034 (Box 14-15)
    - Early white and Baxter's white, 1969-1979, AFC 2017/001: ph02_035 to ph02_053 (Box 14-15)
    - Ware: Salt, 1979, AFC 2017/001: ph02_054 to ph02_071 (Box 14-15)
    - Jugtown SS, 1978, AFC 2017/001: ph02_072 to ph02_082 (Box 14-15)
    - Ware salt, 1978, AFC 2017/001: ph02_083 to ph02_101 (Box 14-15)
    - Jugtown wares various times - CT and Nancy Sweezy, 1979-1980, AFC 2017/001: ph02_102 to ph02_113 (Box 14-15)
    - White, frogskin, and salt, 1979, AFC 2017/001: ph02_114 to ph02_123 (Box 14-15)
    - Frogskin, 1969-1979, AFC 2017/001: ph02_124 to ph02_141 (Box 14-15)
    - Jugtown ware - various, 1978, AFC 2017/001: ph02_142 to ph02_153 (Box 14-15)
    - C6, 1980, AFC 2017/001: ph02_154 to ph02_173 (Box 14-15)
    - Unlabeled, undated, AFC 2017/001: ph02_174 to ph02_249 (Box 14-15)
    - Old Jugtown ware, 1978, AFC 2017/001: ph03_001 to ph03_014 (Box 15-16)
    - Old Jugtown ware at Bluethenthals, 1978, AFC 2017/001: ph03_015 to ph03_030 (Box 15-16)
    - Salt ware, 1980, AFC 2017/001: ph03_031 to ph03_047 (Box 15-16)
    - Orange and buff earthenware, 1978, AFC 2017/001: ph03_048 to ph03_060 (Box 15-16)
    - Orange and buff earthenware, undated, AFC 2017/001: ph03_061 to ph03_073 (Box 15-16)
    - SS Jugtown, 1978, AFC 2017/001: ph03_074 to ph03_092 (Box 15-16)
    - Salt ware, 1978, AFC 2017/001: ph03_093 to ph03_103 (Box 15-16)
    - Jugtown, 1979, AFC 2017/001: ph03_104 to ph03_110 (Box 15-16)
    - Jugtown: Charlie Tomkins, 1980, AFC 2017/001: ph03_111 to ph03_116 (Box 15-16)
    - Jugtown SS, 1998, AFC 2017/001: ph03_117 to ph03_129 (Box 15-16)
    - Jugtown pots, undated, AFC 2017/001: ph03_130 to ph03_140 (Box 15-16)
    - Seagrove potters: ML Owens, Joe Owen, Craven, Westmoore, people, and scenes at Jugtown, undated, AFC 2017/001: ph04_001 to ph04_015 (Box 16-17)
    - David Leach workshop at Jugtown, 1978, AFC 2017/001: ph04_016 to ph04_028 (Box 16-17)
    - Jugtown SI, 1978, AFC 2017/001: ph04_029 to ph04_040 (Box 16-17)
    - Unlabeled, 1978, AFC 2017/001: ph04_041 to ph04_088 (Box 16-17)
    - Folk Festival / Elizabeth "Libba" Cotten- Durham, North Carolina, 1976, AFC 2017/001: ph04_089 to ph04_104 (Box 16-17)
    - People and events - Various Times, 1978-1980, AFC 2017/001: ph04_105 to ph04_122 (Box 16-17)
    - Potters party at Jugtown, 1983, AFC 2017/001: ph04_123 to ph04_158 (Box 16-17)
    - Jugtown scenes, 1968-1980, AFC 2017/001: ph04_159 to ph04_172 (Box 16-17)
    - Leach workshop at Jugtown, 1978, AFC 2017/001: ph04_173 to ph04_188 (Box 16-17)
    - Joan Mondale, 1977, AFC 2017/001: ph04_189 to ph04_204 (Box 16-17)
    - Melvin Owens, 1976, AFC 2017/001: ph04_205 to ph04_237 (Box 16-17)
    - Unlabeled, 1978, AFC 2017/001: ph04_238 to ph04_247 (Box 16-17)
    - Joe Owen SS, undated, AFC 2017/001: ph04_248 to ph04_264 (Box 16-17)
    - Scenes, 1978, AFC 2017/001: ph04_265 to ph04_278 (Box 16-17)
    - Westmoore pots, undated, AFC 2017/001: ph04_279 to ph04_289 (Box 16-17)
    - Pottery trip - England, 1978, AFC 2017/001: ph05_001 to ph05_101 (Box 17-18)
    - England Michael Cardew, 1978, AFC 2017/001: ph05_102 to ph05_121 (Box 17-18)
    - Pottery trip - England, 1978, AFC 2017/001: ph05_122 to ph05_140 (Box 17-18)
    - Jugtown, undated, AFC 2017/001: ph23_086 to ph23_108 (Box 44)
    - England trip, 1976, AFC 2017/001: ph24_045 to ph24_048; film negatives, color; 35 mm. (Box 45)
    - Pottery, 1977, AFC 2017/001: ph24_058 to ph24_059; film negatives, color; 35 mm. (Box 45)
  - Subseries 3: Audio and Video
    - A.R. Cole; Sanford, North Carolina, 1973-07-15, AFC 2017/001: SR001; 1 audio cassette
    - Vernon Owens on turning, 1978-01-13, AFC 2017/001: SR002; 1 audio cassette
    - Norman Smith; Lawley, Alabama, 1978-03-28, AFC 2017/001: SR003; 1 audio cassette
    - Playing music: Ralph Rinzler - mandolin, John Almquist - fiddle, Charlie Tompkins and Vernon Owens - guitar; Jugtown Pottery, 1978-05-10, AFC 2017/001: SR004; 1 audio cassette
    - David Leach workshop, 1978-06-27, AFC 2017/001: SR005; 1 audio cassette
    - Side one: David Leach workshop / Side two: Music with Doc and Merle; Durham Black and Blues concert, backporch, 1978-06-27, AFC 2017/001: SR006; 1 audio cassette
    - Side one: Vernon Owens on guitar (1978), end with Back Porch (1979-06-02) / Side two: Vernon Owens seminar (1978-10-21); Vernon Owens salt glaze talk at kiln, 1978-10-21, AFC 2017/001: SR007; 1 audio cassette
    - Side one: Vernon Owens, Carter, Circle / Side two: Circle; Songs: Mother Maybelle Carter, "Will the Circle be Unbroken", 1978, AFC 2017/001: SR008; 1 audio cassette
    - Side one: Vernon Owens turning / Side two: music, 1978, AFC 2017/001: SR009; 1 audio cassette
    - Jugtown; Charles Tompkins Box 162, undated, AFC 2017/001: MV12; 1 videotape
- Series 3: Southern Pottery Interviews; Raised in Clay, 1967-1995, Bulk: 1981-1994
  - Subseries 1: Manuscripts and Photographic Prints
    - Bob Sayers interview with the Meaders - interview notes, 1967 (Box-folder 51/5)
    - Bob Sayers interview with Lanier Meaders notes, 1968 (Box-folder 51/6)
    - Bob Sayers interviews with North Carolina potters notes, 1968 (Box-folder 51/7)
    - JB Cole Pottery (Seagrove, North Carolina) notes, 1967-1982 (Box-folder 51/8)
    - EJ Brown interviewed by Georgiana Greer with Dorothy Auman (Connelly Springs, North Carolina) transcript, 1973 (Box-folder 51/9)
    - Southwest Potters and Tennessee Basketmakers, 1982-1983, 9 photographic prints (Box-folder 5/2)
    - Raised in Clay, 1981-1983, 34 photographic prints (Box-folder 5/3)
    - Raised in Clay: Potluck, Westmore, GF Cole, Teague, AR Cole, JB Cole, Seagrove, 1981-1983, 91 photographic prints (Box-folder 6/1)
    - Clay Digging in North Carolina contact sheets, undated, 7 photographic prints (Box-folder 86/10)
    - Southeast pottery contact sheets, undated, 68 photographic prints (Box-folder 87/1)
    - Southern Potters and Tom Jackson contact sheets, undated, 76 photographic prints (Box-folder 87/2-3)
    - Bertie Moore (Seagrove, North Carolina) notes, 1979 (Box-folder 51/10)
    - Valerie Nicholson notes, 1981 (Box-folder 51/11)
    - Interviews and background notes - Vernon Owens, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 51/12)
    - William Reeder at Jugtown - interview notes, 1981 (Box-folder 51/13)
    - Teague's Pottery (Robbins, North Carolina) - interview notes, 1981 (Box-folder 52/1)
    - Waymon Cole (Asheboro, North Carolina) - interview notes, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 52/2)
    - Robert Armfield of Oakland Pottery (Ramseur, North Carolina) - interview notes, 1982 (Box-folder 52/3)
    - Auman family - interview notes, 1982 (Box-folder 52/4)
    - Evan and Mercedes Brown at Evan's Pottery (Skylandm, North Carolina) - interview notes, 1982 (Box-folder 52/5)
    - Brown family at Brown's Pottery (Arden, North Carolina) - interview notes, 1982 (Box-folder 52/6)
    - Bybee Pottery (Waco, Kentucky) - interview notes, 1982 (Box-folder 52/7)
    - Katherine Case of Pisgah Forest Pottery (Arden, North Carolina) - interview notes, 1982 (Box-folder 52/8)
    - AR Cole Pottery (Sanford, North Carolina) - interview notes, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 52/9)
    - Connor's Pottery (Ashland, Miss) - interview notes, 1982 (Box-folder 52/10)
    - General Foister "GF" Cole (Sanford, North Carolina) - interview notes, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 52/11)
    - Burlon Craig (Vale, North Carolina) - interview notes, 1982 (Box-folder 52/12)
    - Charlie Craven (Raleigh, North Carolina) - interview notes, 1982 (Box-folder 52/13)
    - Craven Pottery (Gillsville, Georgia) - interview notes, 1982 (Box-folder 52/14)
    - Bill Gordy (Cartersville, Georgia) - interview notes, 1982 (Box-folder 53/1)
    - DX Gordy (Primrose, Georgia) - interview notes, 1982 (Box-folder 53/2)
    - Harwood Graves (Fork Creek, North Carolina) - interview notes, 1982 (Box-folder 53/3)
    - Hewell's Pottery (Gillsville, Georgia) - interview notes, 1982 (Box-folder 53/4)
    - Emeyl Jenkins at Jugtown - interview notes, 1982 (Box-folder 53/5)
    - Jack Kiser (Seagrove, North Carolina) - interview notes, 1982 (Box-folder 53/6)
    - Cleater Meaders (Cleveland, Georgia) - interview notes, 1982 (Box-folder 53/7)
    - Edwin Meaders (Cleveland, Georgia) - interview notes, 1982 (Box-folder 53/8)
    - Lanier Meaders (Cleveland, Georgia) - interview notes, 1982 (Box-folder 53/9)
    - Miller Pottery (Brent, Alabama) - interview notes, 1982 (Box-folder 53/10)
    - Joe Owen (Seagrove, North Carolina) - interview notes, 1982 (Box-folder 53/11)
    - Melvin L Owens (Seagrove, North Carolina) - interview notes, 1982 (Box-folder 53/12)
    - Shearwater Pottery (Ocean Springs, Mississippi) - interview notes, 1982 (Box-folder 53/13)
    - Norman Smith (Lawley, Alabama) - interview notes, 1982 (Box-folder 53/14)
    - Gerald Stewart (Louisville, Mississippi) - interview notes, 1982 (Box-folder 53/15)
    - James G Teague (Seagrove, North Carolina) - interview notes, 1982 (Box-folder 53/16)
    - Laura Teague Moore (Seagrove, North Carolina) - interview notes, 1982 (Box-folder 53/17)
    - Westmoore Pottery (Seagrove, North Carolina) - interview notes, 1982 (Box-folder 53/18)
    - Wilson Pottery (Alto, Georgia) - interview notes, 1982 (Box-folder 53/19)
    - Boyce Yow - interview notes, 1982 (Box-folder 53/20)
    - Boggs Pottery (Prattville, Alabama) - interview notes, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 53/21)
    - Jerry Brown (Hamilton, Alabama) - interview notes, 1983 (Box-folder 53/22)
    - Marshall Pottery (Marshall, Texas) - interview notes, 1983 (Box-folder 54/1)
    - Marie Rodgers (Meansville, Georgia) - interview notes, 1983 (Box-folder 54/2)
    - Arie Meaders (unknown time/interviewer) - interview notes, undated (Box-folder 54/3)
    - Southern pottery interviews resources - traditional, undated (Box-folder 54/4)
    - Historical information regarding North Carolina potters from Dot Auman, undated (Box-folder 54/5)